
// creating an array and passing the number, questions, options and answers

let questions = [
    {
    numb: 1,
    question: "Which keyword is used to prevent any changes in the variable within a C program?",
    answer: "Const",
    options: [
      "Immutable",
      "Mutable",  
      "Const",
      "Volatile"
    ]
  },
    {
    numb: 2,
    question: "What is an example of iteration in C?",
    answer: "All of the mentioned",
    options: [
      "for",
      "While",
      "do-While",
      "All of the mentioned"
    ]
  },
    {
    numb: 3,
    question: "C preprocessors can have compiler specific features.",
    answer: "True",
    options: [
      "True",
      "False",
      "Depends on the standard",
      "Depends on the platform"
    ]
  },
    {
    numb: 4,
    question: "The C preprocessors are specified with _______ symbol.",
    answer: "#",
    options: [
      "#",
      "$",
      "*",
      "&"
    ]
  },
    {
    numb: 5,
    question: "How many number of pointers does C have against a pointer variable declaration?",
    answer: "No limits",
    options: [
      "7",
      "127",
      "255",
      "No limits"
    ]
  },
  {
    numb: 6,
    question: "Which symbol is used as a statement terminator in C?",
    answer: ";",
    options: [
      "!",
      "#",
      "~",
      ";"
    ]
  },
  {
    numb: 7,
    question: "Which of the following is an exit controlled loop?",
    answer: "do-While loop",
    options: [
      "While loop",
      "for loop",
      "do-While loop",
      "None of the above"
    ]
  },
  {
    numb: 8,
    question: "String constants should be enclosed between",
    answer: "Double Quotes",
    options: [
      "Single Quotes",
      "Double Quotes",
      "Both a and b",
      "None of these"
    ]
  },
  {
    numb: 9,
    question: "What will be the maximum size of a float variable in c?",
    answer: "4 bytes",
    options: [
      "1 byte",
      "2 bytes",
      "4 bytes",
      "8 bytes"
    ]
  },
  {
    numb: 10,
    question: "The equality operator is represented in c as",
    answer: "==",
    options: [
      ":=",
      "=",
      "!=",
      "=="
    ]
  },
  {
    numb: 11,
    question: "The operator && is an example for _______ operator",
    answer: "Logical",
    options: [
      "Assignment",
      "Increment",
      "Logical",
      "Rational"
    ]
  },
  {
    numb: 12,
    question: "Which operator has the highest priority in c?",
    answer: "++",
    options: [
      "++",
      "%",
      "+",
      "||"
    ]
  },
  {
    numb: 13,
    question: "Explicit type conversion is known as ",
    answer: "Casting",
    options: [
      "Casting",
      "Conversion",
      "Disjunction",
      "Separation"
    ]
  },
  {
    numb: 14,
    question: "Which pair of functions below are used for single character I/O?",
    answer: "Getchar() and putchar()",
    options: [
      "Getchar() and putchar()",
      "Scanf() and printf()",
      "Input() and Output()",
      "None of these"
    ]
  },
  {
    numb: 15,
    question: "Array subscripts in C always start at ",
    answer: "0",
    options: [
      "1",
      "-1",
      "0",
      "Value provided by the user"
    ]
  },
];